<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<chapter id="architecture">
  <title>Architecture</title>
  
  <para>Intuit Tank is designed as a multi tier, service based
  application. It is designed to be run in a cloud environment where
  access to certain cloud-based services is assumed.</para>
  
  
  <section>
    <title>Cloud Services Used</title>
    
    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>EC2</term>
          <listitem>
            Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) is the service that is used to create compute resources to drive load (agents). 
            There are several parts of this service used.
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    Instances are the actual compute resources used to run load.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Security Groups are used to control access to and from the agent instances and the controller instance.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    AMIs are used as the templates for instantiating new resources.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Load balancers are used to distribute load to the controller.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Elastic IPs are used to bind specific IP addresses to agent instances and can be used in 
                    firewall rules to allow access from agents to the datacenter.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Volumes are used for persisted data that is not stored in S3.
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
          </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>S3</term>
          <listitem>
            Simple Storage Service is used to store document-based items such as data files and response time reports.
          </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>DynamoDb</term>
          <listitem>
            DynamoDb is a key value data store used to collect response metrics during the execution of a test. 
            They are typically aggregated after the test is run.
          </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      
      <varlistentry>
        <term>RDS</term>
          <listitem>
            Relational Data Service (Mysql) is used to store the meta data about the projects including scripts, 
            filters, and project configuration used by the controller.
          </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      
      <varlistentry>
        <term>IAM</term>
          <listitem>
            Identity and access management is used to control access and permissions to cloud resources.
          </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    
    </variablelist>
  
    <para>Most of the above service can be replaced using local services if need be.</para>
  
  
  </section>

</chapter>
