<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<chapter id="data_file">
  <title>Datafiles</title>

  <para>Data Files are external sources of data for your scripts. The lines will get evenly divided up among the agents
    for use.</para>

  <para>
    Clicking the
    <code>Data Files</code>
    tab takes the user to the main screen, which lists all the previously created
    Data Files.
  </para>
  
  <para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/datafiles/datafiles_1.png" format="PNG" align="Center" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </para>

  <para>
    Currently, Intuit Tank supports data files with CSV (Comma Separated Values), and XML format only. The data file is read
    into
    shared memory only once, even if it is read by multiple virtual users. Usually you will use one of the functions
    below only once in your script for each file you load. The following two functions can be used in Intuit Tank to read
    a file:</para>
  <variablelist>
    <varlistentry>
      <term>#{ioFunctions.getCSVData(COLUMN_NUMBER)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This function is used to read a default data file associated with the project. A Data File is default if
          there is only one in a particular job.</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>


    <varlistentry>
      <term>#{ioFunctions.getCSVData('FILE_NAME', COLUMN_NUMBER)</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>This function can be used to read a specific data file when you have to read from multiple data files used
          for
          the same script or multiple scripts in a project (i.e. separate data files for personal information and
          login
          credentials).</para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
  <note>
    <para>Column Number 0 represents the 1st column in the file.</para>
  </note>
  <tip>
    <para>It is important that all the user data files needed by your test script are added to your project.</para>
  </tip>
  
  <para>Clicking on the magnify icon will allow you to see the contents of the data file.</para>
  <para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/datafiles/datafiles_2.png" format="PNG" align="Center" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </para>

  <section>
    <title>Uploading Data Files</title>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>In the Data Files Tab, click the Upload link to add data files. The Upload Data Files dialog box opens.
        </para>
        <para>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/datafiles/datafiles_3.png" format="PNG" align="Center" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>From the Upload Data Files dialog box, click Choose to navigate to and select the data file(s) or zip archives to add to
          the project. If a zip archive is uploaded, Intuit Tank will recursively upload all files with the ".csv" extension. 
        </para>
        <para>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/datafiles/datafiles_4.png" format="PNG" align="Center" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Click either Upload or the arrow next to the box to upload the data file. You can also click the cancel
          button if you choose not to upload the data file. 
        </para>
        <para>
          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/datafiles/datafiles_5.png" format="PNG" align="Center" />
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </para>
      </listitem>

    </orderedlist>


  </section>


</chapter>
