<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


<chapter id="tools">
  <title>Tools</title>

  <para>Intuit Tank includes several external tools that can be used in conjunction with Intuit Tank.</para>

  <para>
    Clicking the
    <code>Tools</code>
    tab takes the user to the main screen, which has links to downloads and pages for launching the tools as java
    applets.
  </para>
  <para>
    There are two sections of links for the tools, Applets and Downlaodable Tools.
  </para>

  <para>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/tools/tools_1.png" format="PNG" align="Center" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </para>

  <section>
    <title>Applets</title>
    <para> Applets are rich clients that are run using java Applet technology. they access system resources so are
      signed using a self signed certificate. This will prompt you to trust the applet when you launch it.
    </para>
    <para>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="images/tools/tools_2.png" format="PNG" align="Center" />
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </para>


    <section>
      <title>Intuit Tank Agent Visual Debugger</title>
      <para> The Intuit Tank Agent Visual Debugger allows for the debugging of scripts or projects in a visual manner.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Intuit Tank Script Filter Editor</title>
      <para>The Intuit Tank Script Filter Editor allows for the editing and creation and testing of filter scripts
        (external scripts) in a visual environment
      </para>
    </section>

  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Downloadable Tools</title>
    <para> Downloadable Tools are meant to be run from your local machine. They require that java is installed on your
      local machine.
    </para>


    <section>
      <title>Intuit Tank Agent Visual Debugger</title>
      <para> The Intuit Tank Agent Visual Debugger is downloaded as an executable jar file. It may be run by double
        clicking on the jar or by running from the command line. If run from the command line, you can additionally
        specify the url of Intuit Tank you wish to connect to. e.g. java -jar Tank-Debugger-all.jar http://my.tank/tank
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Intuit Tank Script Filter Editor</title>
      <para>The Intuit Tank Script Filter Editor allows for the editing and creation and testing of filter scripts
        (external scripts) in a visual environment
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Intuit Tank Proxy Package</title>
      <para>The proxy package is a zip file that contains the proxy recorder. See the readme.txt file for instructions on setup.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Api Test Harness Debugger Package</title>
      <para>Command line debugger for agent scripts.
      </para>
    </section>

  </section>

</chapter>
